Guide to the Max Lerner Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence, 1935-1969; Series I
  - Selected Correspondence
    - Greene, Graham, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 162)
    - Griffin, Robert P., 1969 (Box 3, Folder 163)
    - Gunther, John, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 164)
    - Hackett, Francis, 1944, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 165)
    - Hall, Gordon D., 1952, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Hand, Learned, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Handlin, Oscar, 1949, 1955, undated (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Hannegan, Robert E., 1944 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Hansberry, Lorraine, 1959, 1966, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Harper and Row
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 60
    - Harriman, Averill, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Hartz, Louis, 1952-1957 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Havighurst, Robert, 1952, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Hatch, Robert, 1948-1952 (Box 4, Folder 174 - 177)
    - Haydn, Hiram, 1944-1957 (Box 4, Folder 178 - 182)
    - Hefner, Hugh, 1968, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 183)
    - Helms, Richard, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 184)
    - Hillman, Sidney, 1944, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 185)
    - Hirschman, Ira A., 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 186)
    - Hobson, Laura Z., 1948, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 187)
    - Hofstadter, Richard, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 188)
    - Holcomber, Arthur N., 1946, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 189)
    - Howard University, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 190 - 191)
    - Howe, Mark DeW., 1941, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    - Hughes, Emmet John, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 193)
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1949-1968 (Box 4, Folder 194 - 195)
    - Hutchins, Robert M., 1949, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 196)
    - Ickes, Harold L., 1944 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - Indiana State Teachers Association, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Interior, Department of the
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 197
    - Janowitz, Morris, Undated (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - Javits, Jacob K., 1966, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - Jencks, Christopher, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Johnson, Alvin, 1949, 1955, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - Johnson, Wallace, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - Jones, Lewis, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - Kahn, Herman, 1965, 1967, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - Kempton, Murray, 1954, undated (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - Kennan, George, 1950, 1954-1955, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - Kennedy, John F., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 208)
    - Kennedy, Robert
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 266
    - Kingsley, J. Donald, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Kinsey, Alfred C., 1950-1954 (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - Kirchway, Freda, 1939-1950 (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - Klein, Julius, 1967 July-September (Box 4, Folder 212 - 213)
    - Knopf, Alfred A., 1936-1950, undated (Box 4, Folder 214)
    - Kristol, Irving, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - Krock, Arthur, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 216)
    - LaGuardia, Fiorello, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    - Landers, Ann, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - Landon, Alf M., 1968 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - Laski, Frida (Mrs. Harold), 1945-1958, undated (Box 5, Folder 220)
    - Laski, Harold, 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 221)
    - Laski, Harold J., 1940-1950 (Box 5, Folder 222 - 226)
    - Laski Fund, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 227 - 228)
    - Lasky, Melvin J., 1957, 1960, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 229)
    - Lasswell, Herbert, 1953, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 230)
    - Lerner, Alan Jay, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 231)
    - Lerner, Anita Marburg, Undated (Box 5, Folder 232)
    - Levin, Meyer, 1955-1966 (Box 5, Folder 233)
    - Levy, Leonard, 1952-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 234 - 235)
    - Lewis, John L., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 236)
    - Lewis, John P., Undated (Box 5, Folder 237)
    - Lindner, Robert, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 238 - 239)
    - Lindsay, John V., 1961-1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 240)
    - Little, Brown and Company, 1939-1953 (Box 5, Folder 241 - 249)
    - Los Angeles, mayor of
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 49
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 463
    - Los Angeles Times, 1967-1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 250)
    - Lubell, Samuel, 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 251)
    - Lynd, Helen M., 1949, 1958, 1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 252)
    - Lynd, Robert S., 1943-1955 (Box 5, Folder 253)
    - Lynd, Staughton, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 254)
    - Lyons, Leonard, 1957, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 255)
    - McCarthy, Eugene J., 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 256)
    - McDonald, David J., 1959 (Box 5, Folder 257)
    - McDonald, Dwight, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 258)
    - McDougal, Myers S., 1949 (Box 5, Folder 259)
    - McGill, Ralph, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - McGovern, George S., 1965 (Box 5, Folder 261)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1942-1955 (Box 5, Folder 262)
    - Mailer, Norman, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 263)
    - Malraux, André, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 264)
    - Manchester, William, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 265)
    - Mankiewicz, Frank, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 266)
    - Mansfield, Mike, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 267)
    - Manuel, Frank E., 1969 (Box 5, Folder 268)
    - Marcuse, Herbert, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 269)
    - Marin, Luis Munoz, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 270)
    - Maritain, Jacques, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 271)
    - Martin, Kingsley, 1949-1954 (Box 6, Folder 272)
    - Marshall, Thurgood, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 273)
    - Marshall, College, 1952 (Box 6, Folder 274)
    - Marty, Martin E., 1962 (Box 6, Folder 275)
    - Mason, Alpheus Thomas, 1945-1948 (Box 6, Folder 276)
    - Masterson, Charles F., 1956 (Box 6, Folder 277)
    - Mayer, Arthur L., 1952 (Box 6, Folder 278)
    - Mayer, J. P., 1956-1967 (Box 6, Folder 279)
    - Mead, Margaret, 1955, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 280)
    - Mebane, Daniel, 1942-1952 (Box 6, Folder 281)
    - Meiklejohn, Alexander, 1943-1948, undated (Box 6, Folder 282 - 283)
    - Meir, Golda, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 284)
    - Mendes-France, Pierre, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 285)
    - Menninger, Karl A., 1949, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 286)
    - Michener, James, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 287)
    - Miller, Henry, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 288)
    - Miller, Perry, 1951-1956 (Box 6, Folder 289)
    - Mills, C. Wright, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 290)
    - Minnesota Education Association, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 291 - 292)
    - Mondale, Walter, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 293)
    - Monnet, Jean, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 294)
    - Montagu, Ashley, 1956-1957 (Box 6, Folder 295)
    - Morganthau, Hans J., 1954, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 296)
    - Morganthau, Henry, Jr., 1946 (Box 6, Folder 297)
    - Morison, Samuel Eliot, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 298)
    - Morris, Newbold, 1945, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 299)
    - Morse, Wayne, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 300)
    - Moyers, Bill D., 1967, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 301)
    - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 302)
    - Mumford, Lewis, 1945-1957 (Box 6, Folder 303 - 304)
    - Murphy, Thomas, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 305)
    - Muskie, Edmund S., 1969 (Box 6, Folder 306)
    - Muste, A. J., 1946, 1948, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 307)
    - The Nation
      General note
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 211
    - National Review
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 53
    - Navy, Department of the
    - Neff, Emery, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 308)
    - Nettels, Curtis, 1946-1949 (Box 6, Folder 309)
    - The New Republic, 1943-1963, undated (Box 6, Folder 310 - 311)
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 35 - 40
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 104
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 174 - 177
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 281
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 403
    - New School for Social Research
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 105
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 202
    - New York, city of
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 299
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 305
    - New York, City University of
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 46
    - New York, mayor of
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 240
    - New York Post
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 357 - 358
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 448 - 449
    - The New York Star, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 312)
    - The New York Times, 1945, 1958-1959, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 313)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1953-1954 (Box 6, Folder 314)
    - Nixon, Richard M., 1966 (Box 6, Folder 315)
    - Nizer, Louis, 1956, 1958, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 316)
    - Oates, J. Whitney, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 317)
    - Office of Price Administration
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 47 - 48
    - Office of War Information
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 329
    - Oxnam, G. Bromley, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 318)
    - Parsons, Talcott, 1956-1957, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 319)
    - Pekelis, Alexander H., 1943-1946 (Box 6, Folder 320)
    - Pennsylvania, University of, Law Review, 1958-1959 (Box 6, Folder 321)
    - Pepper, Claude, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 322)
    - Peretz, Martin, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 323)
    - Perkins, Dexter, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 324)
    - Perkins, Frances, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 325)
    - Perry, Bernard, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 326)
    - Phi Beta Kappa, United Chapters of
    - Philadelphia, mayor of
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 413
    - Philbrick, Herbert A., 1953 (Box 6, Folder 327)
    - Pike, James A., 1954, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 328)
    - Pringle, Henry F., 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 329)
    - Pritchett, C. Herman, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 330)
    - Radio Broadcasts, miscellaneous, 1944-1947 (Box 6, Folder 331)
    - Random House
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 67
    - Reston, James, 1967, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 332)
    - Reuther, Walter, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 333)
    - Rey, Luis Esteban, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 334)
    - Riesman, David, 1952-1959, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 335)
    - Roche, John P., 1956, 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 336)
    - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 337)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1960-1961, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 338)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Mrs. Franklin D.), 1945-1960 (Box 7, Folder 339)
    - Roosevelt, Elliot, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 340)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin, Jr., 1946 (Box 7, Folder 341)
    - Rosen, Robert, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 342)
    - Roseman, Samuel I., 1942, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 343)
    - Rosten, Norman, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 344)
    - Rossiter, Clinton, 1953, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 345)
    - Rostow, Eugene V., 1945-1946, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 346)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 347)
    - Rutledge, Wiley, 1947, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 348)
    - Ratcliffe, S. K., 1954 (Box 7, Folder 349)
    - Rosten, Leo, 1965, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 350)
    - Sachar, A. L., 1953-1965 (Box 7, Folder 351)
    - St. Louis Post-Dispatch
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 93
    - Salinger, Pierre, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 352)
    - Sandburg, Carl, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 353)
    - Sarah Lawrence College
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 418
    - Sartre, Jean Paul, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 354)
    - Saturday Review of Literature
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 84
    - Saveth, Edward N., 1955-1956, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 355)
    - Schechter, Edmund, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 356)
    - Schiff, Dorothy, 1953-1969 (Box 7, Folder 357 - 358)
    - Shils, Edward, 1953, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 359)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1947-1969 (Box 7, Folder 360 - 361)
    - Schuman, Frederick, 1946-1962 (Box 7, Folder 362 - 363)
    - Seeley, John R., 1967 (Box 7, Folder 364)
    - Seldes, George, 1943-1955 (Box 7, Folder 365)
    - Shriver, R. Sargent, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 366)
    - Simon and Schuster
      - 1945-1958 February 28 (Box 7, Folder 367 - 380)
      - 1958-1969, undated (Box 8, Folder 381 - 388)
    - Sinclair, Upton, 1935, 1949, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 389)
    - Smedley, Agnes, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 390)
    - Smith, Herman Dunlap, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 391)
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 398
    - Snow, Edgar, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 392)
    - South Dakota Education Association, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 393)
    - Spanel, Abraham N., 1943-1944, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 394)
    - Sparkman, John, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 395)
    - Stanton, Frank, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 396)
    - State, Department of
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 16
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 347
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 397
    - Stettinius, Edward R. Jr., 1944 (Box 8, Folder 397)
    - Stevenson, Adlai E., 1952-1964 (Box 8, Folder 398)
    - Stone, Harlan F., 1943 (Box 8, Folder 399)
    - Stone, I. F., 1947, undated (Box 8, Folder 400)
    - Stover, Carl F., 1959, undated (Box 8, Folder 401)
    - Strachey, John, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 402)
    - Straight, Beatrice, 1947, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 403)
    - Straight, Michael, 1941-1954 (Box 8, Folder 404 - 405)
    - Strauss, Lewis L., 1969 (Box 8, Folder 406)
    - Supreme Court of the United States
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 31 - 34
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 56
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 72
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 97
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 112
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 117 - 137
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 273
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 348
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 399
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 445
    - Sylvester, Arthur, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 407)
    - Syndication Correspondence, 1959, 1960, undated (Box 8, Folder 408 - 411)
    - Szilard, Leo, 1955, 1960, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 412)
    - Tate, James H. J., 1965 (Box 8, Folder 413)
    - Tax, Sol, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 414)
    - Taylor, A. J. P., 1957 (Box 8, Folder 415)
    - Taylor, Elizabeth, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 416)
    - Taylor, Glen H., 1947 (Box 8, Folder 417)
    - Taylor, Harold, 1945-1946 (Box 8, Folder 418)
    - Taylor, Telford, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 419)
    - Thant, U, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 420)
    - Thomas, Norman, 1949, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 421)
    - Thompson, Dorothy, 1944, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 422)
    - Tillich, Hannah (Mrs. Paul J.), 1968 (Box 9, Folder 423)
    - Town Hall, Inc., 1944-1949 (Box 9, Folder 424 - 427)
    - Tonybee, Arnold, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 428)
    - Trilling, Lionel, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 429)
    - Truman, Harry S., 1967 (Box 9, Folder 430)
    - Tuchman, Barbara, 1955, 1957, 1967, undated (Box 9, Folder 431)
      See also: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 326
    - United Mine Workers
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 236
    - United Steelworkers of America
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 257
    - Valenti, Jack, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 432)
    - Viking Press, 1939-1950, undated (Box 9, Folder 433 - 440)
    - Wagner, Robert F., 1944 (Box 9, Folder 441)
    - Wallace, Henry A., 1944, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 442)
    - Walsh, Raymond J., 1943, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 443)
    - Warner, W. Lloyd, 1949, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 444)
    - Warren, Earl, 1953-1969 (Box 9, Folder 445)
    - Weiss, Louis S., 1946, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 446)
    - Wertheim, Frederic, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 447)
    - Wechsler, James, 1945-1962, undated (Box 9, Folder 448 - 449)
    - Wheeler, Burton K., 1969 (Box 9, Folder 450)
    - White House aides and assistants
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 52
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 209
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 277
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 301
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 302
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 336
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 343
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 352
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 360 - 361
    - White, Morton, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 451)
    - Whyte, William Foote, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 452)
    - Whyte, William Holly, 1955-1956 (Box 9, Folder 453)
    - Wilkie, Wendell, 1943-1944 (Box 9, Folder 454)
    - Williams College
      See: Series I. Correspondence, 1935-1969 Folder 20
    - Williams, Tennessee, 1956, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 455)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1954, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 456)
    - Winchell, Walter, 1944-1949, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 457)
    - Winter, Ella, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 458)
    - Wisconsin Education Association, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 459)
    - Wise, Stephen S., 1947 (Box 9, Folder 460)
    - Woodward, C. Vann, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 461)
    - Yarmolinsky, Adam, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 462)
    - Yorty, Sam, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 463)
    - Zinn, Howard, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 464)
  - General Correspondence
    - 1936-1949 March 10 (Box 10, Folder 465 - 500)
    - 1949 March 11-1954 Feb, undated (Box 11, Folder 501 - 540)
    - 1954 March 1-1956 January 9 (Box 12, Folder 541 - 580)
    - 1956 January 10-1958 July (Box 13, Folder 581 - 620)
    - 1958 August 1-1961 March 14 (Box 14, Folder 621 - 660)
    - 1961 March 15-1967 November 20 (Box 15, Folder 661 - 695)
    - 1967 November 21-1969 Dec, undated (Box 16, Folder 696 - 719)
- Speeches and Writings, 1927, 1932-1969; Series II
  SPEECHES AND WRITINGS are divided into five sections: newspaper columns, magazine articles, speeches and speech notes, books, and bibliographies. Items are filed chronologically within each section. The notes and draft for a particular column or book are filed with the final copy of the column or book.
  - Newspaper columns
    - PM (14 folders), 1943 January -1946 October (Box 17, Folder 719 - 719m)
    - 1947-1949 November 15 (Box 17a, Folder 720 - 745)
    - 1949 November 16-1950 November 15 (Box 18, Folder 746 - 768)
    - 1950 November 16-1952 February 15 (Box 19, Folder 769 - 793)
    - 1952 February 16-1953 March 15 (Box 20, Folder 794 - 815)
    - 1953 March 16-1954 April 30 (Box 21, Folder 816 - 843)
    - 1954 May 1-1955 April 30 (Box 22, Folder 844 - 865)
    - 1955 May 1-1956 April 15 (Box 23, Folder 866 - 888)
    - 1956 April 16-1957 February 28 (Box 24, Folder 889 - 913)
    - 1957 March 1-1958 January 31 (Box 25, Folder 914 - 934)
    - 1958 February 1-1958 December 31 (Box 26, Folder 935 - 962)
      Includes notes for 1958 columns.
    - 1959 January-1960 June 15 (Box 27, Folder 963 - 993)
    - 1960 June 16-December 31 (Box 28, Folder 994 - 1017)
      Includes 1960 undated columns and notes for columns.
    - 1961 January 1-1962 March 10 (Box 29, Folder 1018 - 1043)
    - 1962 Mar 11-Oct 25, 1962 March 11-October 25 (Box 30, Folder 1044 - 1068)
    - 1962 October 26-December 31 (Box 31, Folder 1069 - 1089)
      Includes 1962 undated columns.
    - 1962, 1963 January 1-July 31 (Box 32, Folder 1090 - 1113)
    - 1963 August 1-1964 June 21 (Box 33, Folder 1114 - 1140)
    - 1964 June 22-1965 January 17 (Box 34, Folder 1141 - 1163)
    - 1965 January 18-August 8 (Box 35, Folder 1164 - 1189)
    - 1965 August 9-1966 January 11 (Box 36, Folder 1190 - 1214)
    - 1966 January 12-May 31 (Box 37, Folder 1215 - 1235)
    - 1966 June 1-November 30 (Box 38, Folder 1236 - 1258)
    - 1966 December 1-1967 March 28 (Box 39, Folder 1259 - 1280)
    - 1967 March 29-June 25 (Box 40, Folder 1281 - 1298)
    - 1967 June 26-October 10 (Box 41, Folder 1299 - 1318)
    - 1967 October 11-1968 January 28 (Box 42, Folder 1319 - 1339)
    - 1968 January 29-May 19 (Box 43, Folder 1340 - 1362)
    - 1968 May 20-August 31 (Box 44, Folder 1363 - 1385)
    - 1968 September 1-December 26 (Box 45, Folder 1386 - 1411)
    - 1968 December 27-1969 April 6 (Box 46, Folder 1412 - 1433)
    - 1969 April 7-July 27 (Box 47, Folder 1434 - 1458)
    - 1969 July 28-November 16 (Box 48, Folder 1459 - 1482)
    - 1969 November 17-December 31, undated (Box 49, Folder 1483 - 1498)
    - Indices, 1949-1955 (Box 49, Folder 1499 - 1500)
    - Alphabetical index, 1949-1956 (Box 50, Folder 1501 - 1502)
    - Indices, 1956-1960 (Box 50, Folder 1503 - 1506)
  - Magazine articles
    - List of published articles, 1928-1949 (Box 51, Folder 1507)
    - 1927-1953 (Box 51, Folder 1508 - 1527)
    - 1953-1969, undated (Box 52, Folder 1528 - 1547)
    - Undated (Box 53, Folder 1548 - 1563)
  - Speeches and notes
    - 1935 (Box 54, Folder 1564)
    - 1938 (Box 54, Folder 1565)
    - 1941-1949 (Box 54, Folder 1566 - 1574)
    - 1952-1957 (Box 54, Folder 1575 - 1587)
    - 1957 (Box 55, Folder 1588)
    - 1958 (Box 55, Folder 1589 - 1591)
    - 1959-1962 (Box 55, Folder 1592 - 1598)
    - 1964-1967 (Box 55, Folder 1599 - 1603)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 56, Folder 1604 - 1608)
    - Undated (Box 56, Folder 1609)
    - Introduction to Politics, Sarah Lawrence College, 1932-1935 (Box 56, Folder 1610 - 1615)
    - Lectures on American history - Harvard Summer School and Williams College (Box 56, Folder 1616 - 1617)
    - Notes on Tolstoy's novels - Sarah Lawrence College (Box 57, Folder 1618)
    - 1945 (Box 57, Folder 1619 - 1620)
    - 1947-1948 (Box 57, Folder 1621)
    - 1955 (Box 57, Folder 1622 - 1624)
    - 1958 (Box 57, Folder 1625 - 1626)
    - 1958 October (Box 57, Folder 1627 - 1628)
    - Literature and American Civilization, 1958 (Box 57, Folder 1629)
    - 1958 (Box 57, Folder 1630 - 1632)
    - 1959 (Box 57, Folder 1633 - 1635)
    - Law and American Civilization, 1960 (Box 57, Folder 1636)
    - 1960 (Box 57, Folder 1637)
    - 1960 (Box 58, Folder 1638 - 1641)
    - Minnesota Education Association, 1960 (Box 58, Folder 1642)
    - M.I.T. Centenary Lecture, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 1643)
    - 1961 (Box 58, Folder 1644 - 1645)
    - 1962 (Box 58, Folder 1646)
    - Ford Hall Lecture, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 1647)
    - 1966 (Box 58, Folder 1648)
    - Meet the Press - Benjamin Spock and William Sloane Coffin, Jr., 1968 (Box 58, Folder 1649)
    - Lecture notes - Williams College (Box 58, Folder 1650)
    - Lecture notes - Brandeis University (Box 58, Folder 1651 - 1655)
    - Lectures on Lincoln Steffens and the Muckrakers - Princeton University (Box 58, Folder 1656 - 1657)
    - Undated (Box 58, Folder 1658)
    - Undated (Box 59, Folder 1659 - 1672)
    - Undated (Box 60, Folder 1673 - 1678)
  - Books
    - The State-unpublished manuscript, 1929-1930 (Box 61, Folder 1679 - 1682)
    - Burden of Government Business-unpublished manuscript, Undated (Box 61, Folder 1683 - 1685)
    - It Is Later Than You Think - first draft and proof, 1938 (Box 61, Folder 1686 - 1692)
    - Ideas Are Weapons - notes and drafts, 1939 (Box 61, Folder 1693)
    - "The New Federalist" - unpublished forward, notes, and finished chapters, 1941 (Box 62, Folder 1694 - 1699)
    - Mind and Faith of Justice Holmes - notes and proof, 1942 (Box 62, Folder 1700 - 1701)
    - Ideas for the Ice Age - mss. and proof, 1943 (Box 63, Folder 1702 - 1712)
    - Introduction to Aristotle's Politics proof, 1943 (Box 64, Folder 1713)
    - "America, America" - mss. unpublished, 1945 (Box 64, Folder 1714)
    - "Letters from America" - mss. unpublished, 1946 (Box 64, Folder 1715)
    - Portable Veblen - notes, draft, and mss., 1947, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 1716 - 1722)
    - Actions and Passions - notes, 1949 (Box 64, Folder 1723 - 1727)
    - Actions and Passions - notes and proof, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 1728 - 1730)
    - Address to the American Nation - mss. unpublished, 1950 (Box 65, Folder 1731 - 1732)
    - "Power and Freedom" - mss. unpublished, 1951 (Box 65, Folder 1733 - 1734)
    - America as a Civilization
      - Notes, 1957 (Box 66, Folder 1735 - 1750)
      - Notes, 1957 (Box 67, Folder 1751 - 1765)
      - Notes, 1957 (Box 68, Folder 1766 - 1781)
      - Notes, 1957 (Box 69, Folder 1782 - 1787)
      - Mss. first draft, 1957 (Box 69, Folder 1788 - 1791)
      - America as Civilization - Brandeis University